{
  "title": "2.6",
  "definitions": {
    "CONFLICT": {
      "word": "CONFLICT",
      "phonetic": "{kon'-flikt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a struggle, battle, quarrel, clash </p><p>CONFLICT comes from a Latin word which means “a striking together.”  A CONFLICT is a situation in which people, nations, events, or interests disagree or interfere with one another. It could be as major as a war or battle. </p><p>“During the CONFLICT ten thousand soldiers lost their lives.” </p><p>Or a CONFLICT could be minor. </p><p>“She had a CONFLICT between Math and English. Both classes met at the same time.” </p><p>CONFLICT is also a verb, meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">clash</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">disagree</i>. </p><p>“Their stories of what happened CONFLICT, so who is telling the truth?” </p><p>“His latest statement CONFLICTS with several earlier statements he made.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen incorrect answer in the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">injury</i>. An <i class=“def-ital\">injury</i> may be the result of a CONFLICT, but the two words do not have the same meaning.</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">con-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "PROSPER": {
      "word": "PROSPER",
      "phonetic": "{pros'-pÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to succeed, flourish </p><p>When someone PROSPERS he is succeeding or doing well. The word usually suggests continued and steadily increasing success. The word often suggests financial success. </p><p>“He PROSPERED in his new business.” </p><p>It can be used about other kinds of success as well. </p><p>“Our cat was sickly for a while, but with the proper medicine and a better diet he began to PROSPER.” </p><p>Things like companies or countries can also PROSPER. </p><p>“The town PROSPERED when the highway was built near it.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROSPERITY, n., PROSPEROUS, adj.</p>"
    },
    "REAP": {
      "word": "REAP",
      "phonetic": "{rEp)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to harvest, gather </p><p>To REAP is to cut down and gather in a crop, especially a crop of grain. </p><p>“They worked all day to REAP the wheat.” </p><p>In a general sense, REAP means “to get or win as a result of your work.” </p><p>“He hoped to REAP the benefits of his college education.” </p><p>“The inventor REAPED a fortune from this machine.”</p>"
    },
    "CAVITY": {
      "word": "CAVITY",
      "phonetic": "{kav'-ÔøΩtE)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a hole, empty space </p><p>CAVITY is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">cave</i>. A CAVITY is a hole, a hollowed-out space in a solid object. A CAVITY in a tooth is a hole caused by decay. </p><p>“In a hidden CAVITY in the wall they found a sack of gold.” </p><p>“The dentist found several CAVITIES in the child’s teeth.” </p><p>Many people pick <i class=“def-ital\">tooth</i> as the meaning of CAVITY on the Pretest. These people have heard the word used, but don’t know its exact meaning. A CAVITY is a hole in a tooth, not the tooth itself.</p>"
    },
    "SHRIVEL": {
      "word": "SHRIVEL",
      "phonetic": "{shriv'-ÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to shrink, wither, dry up and wrinkle </p><p>To SHRIVEL is to shrink in size and become dry and wrinkled. Often something SHRIVELS because of heat. </p><p>“He threw the note into the fireplace where it SHRIVELED up as it burned.” </p><p>Or because of age or illness: “When people get very old, their skin SHRIVELS.” </p><p>“In the old book we found a SHRIVELED leaf which someone had wanted to keep.” </p><p>SHRIVEL can also be used about anything that can be said to dry up and shrink. </p><p>“His once great talent seemed to SHRIVEL with age.” </p><p>Usage: SHRIVEL is often followed by <i class=“def-ital\">up</i>.</p>"
    },
    "SLAY": {
      "word": "SLAY",
      "phonetic": "{slA)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to murder, kill </p><p>To SLAY someone is to put him to death by force, to murder him. SLAY is a literary word, more often used in print than in ordinary conversation. </p><p>“The bank guard was SLAIN by an unknown gunman.” </p><p>“The giant SLEW him with one swing of his mighty fist.” </p><p>Usage: The past tense of SLAY is SLEW. The past participle is SLAIN.</p>"
    },
    "THRASH": {
      "word": "THRASH",
      "phonetic": "(thrash)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to beat, pound, whip; to move violently </p><p>THRASH means to <i class=“def-ital\">beat</i>, usually repeatedly with a stick or whip. </p><p>“In the spring he always had to THRASH the carpets with a rug beater.” </p><p>“Mr. Jones took out his anger at the world by THRASHING his dog.” </p><p>Because the idea of waving the arms about in beating something is included in THRASH, the word has also come to mean simply “to move or toss about violently.” </p><p>“In her sleep Debbie THRASHED around so much that she kicked off all her covers.”</p>"
    },
    "ACQUAINTANCE": {
      "word": "ACQUAINTANCE",
      "phonetic": "(a-kwAn'-tans)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">familiarity; a person one knows slightly </p><p>To be ACQUAINTED with something is to be familiar with it. The word suggests only a slight knowledge, not a deep understanding. </p><p>“He speaks two languages very well and is ACQUAINTED with a dozen more.” </p><p>To be ACQUAINTED with a person is to know him, although usually not very well. </p><p>“I am ACQUAINTED with Bill. I have spoken to him a few times.” ACQUAINTANCE is a noun from ACQUAINT.  ACQUAINTANCE is a general familiarity with something, but not a thorough knowledge. </p><p>“Ralph has some ACQUAINTANCE with legal matters, although he has never studied law.” </p><p>An ACQUAINTANCE is someone you know slightly, not quite a friend. </p><p>Other forms of the word: ACQUAINT, v., ACQUAINTED, adj. </p><p>Usage: ACQUAINTANCE, when it means <i class=“def-ital\">familiarity</i>, is usually followed by <i class=“def-ital\">with</i>.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ance</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "BANQUET": {
      "word": "BANQUET",
      "phonetic": "(bang'-kwit)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a feast, elaborate meal </p><p>A BANQUET is a large, elaborate meal attended by many people. It is usually given in honor of someone or to mark a special occasion. </p><p>“The championship football team was given a large BANQUET to celebrate their victory.” </p><p>“Five hundred people were at the BANQUET to honor Mr. Jones on his retirement.” </p><p>“When he saw all the food and drink on the table he said this wasn’t just a regular meal, it was a BANQUET.”</p>"
    },
    "REDUCE": {
      "word": "REDUCE",
      "phonetic": "(ri-dUs')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to make less, make smaller, lessen, shrink </p><p>To REDUCE something is to make it smaller or less. </p><p>“The driver REDUCED his speed as he went around the corner.” </p><p>“Alice REDUCED her weight by going without lunch.” </p><p>“We must REDUCE the amount of money we spend.” </p><p>“The soldier’s rank was REDUCED from sergeant to corporal.” </p><p>REDUCTION is the noun from REDUCE. </p><p>“There has been a great REDUCTION in the number of mistakes since we started checking the work more carefully.” </p><p>“I will wait for a REDUCTION in the price before I buy it.” </p><p>The most common mistake on the Pretest is to think that REDUCE means <i class=“def-ital\">end</i>. You do not end something by REDUCING it, you just make the size or amount of it smaller. </p><p>Other forms of the word: REDUCTION, n.</p>"
    },
    "BLOATED": {
      "word": "BLOATED",
      "phonetic": "(blO'-tid)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">swollen, puffed up </p><p>When something is BLOATED it is swollen beyond its normal size, usually with a liquid or gas. </p><p>BLOATED usually gives the sense of being puffed up in an unhealthy way. </p><p>“After drinking so much water she felt BLOATED.” </p><p>“Her legs became BLOATED as a result of the disease.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: BLOAT, v.</p>"
    },
    "CLUTCH": {
      "word": "CLUTCH",
      "phonetic": "(kluhch)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to seize, grab </p><p>To CLUTCH something is to seize it and hold on to it tightly, like a bird grasping something in its claws. </p><p>“He CLUTCHED the kitten so tightly that it tried to wriggle free.” </p><p>“The baby CLUTCHED its bottle with both hands.” </p><p>To CLUTCH at something is to try to get hold of it. </p><p>“Whenever she was frightened she would CLUTCH at her mother’s hand.” </p><p>CLUTCH is also a noun, meaning <i class=“def-ital\">grasp</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">control</i>. It is often used in the plural. </p><p>“The child was in the CLUTCHES of evil kidnappers.”</p>"
    },
    "STAGGER": {
      "word": "STAGGER",
      "phonetic": "(stag'-ÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to move unsteadily, totter, sway </p><p>STAGGER means to <i class=“def-ital\">move unsteadily</i> or to <i class=“def-ital\">sway</i>. Someone who is STAGGERING looks as if he is about to fall. </p><p>“The drunken man STAGGERED down the street.” </p><p>“The fighter was hit so hard by his opponent that he STAGGERED.” </p><p>When something STAGGERS you, it almost knocks you down. STAGGER can be used in this sense about news or ideas which astonish or shock. </p><p>“The news of her accident STAGGERED me.” </p><p>“Everyone was STAGGERED by the increase in the cost of living.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Fall down</i> is the most popular wrong answer. Someone who STAGGERS may be about to fall, but STAGGER does not mean to <i class=“def-ital\">fall down</i>.</p>"
    },
    "COMMITMENT": {
      "word": "COMMITMENT",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩmit'-mÔøΩnt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a pledge, obligation, promise </p><p>One meaning of the verb to COMMIT is to <i class=“def-ital\">pledge</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">undertake</i>. </p><p>“The governor has COMMITTED himself to lowering taxes this year.” </p><p>A COMMITMENT is something to which you are pledged, a promise.  </p><p>“She forgot all about her COMMITMENT to sing in the show.” </p><p>“You made a COMMITMENT to help me move this morning. You can’t back out now.” </p><p>COMMITMENT is also the state of being COMMITTED. </p><p>“His COMMITMENT to their cause lessened when they started talking about violence.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: COMMIT, v.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ment</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "DEBRIS": {
      "word": "DEBRIS",
      "phonetic": "(dÔøΩbrE')",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">ruins, rubbish, refuse </p><p>Note the pronunciation. DEBRIS is a French word and keeps its French pronunciation. DEBRIS is the scattered broken pieces of something that has fallen apart or been destroyed. </p><p>“The ground was covered with DEBRIS after the train wreck.” </p><p>“It took weeks to clean up the DEBRIS left behind by the flood.” </p><p>“After the fire there was nothing but DEBRIS where the house had once stood.”</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "6",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "After the CONFLICT.",
          "answers": [
            "injury",
            "fall",
            "storm",
            "game",
            "struggle"
          ],
          "word": "CONFLICT",
          "correct": "struggle"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will all PROSPER.",
          "answers": [
            "succeed",
            "pray",
            "wonder",
            "enjoy",
            "fail"
          ],
          "word": "PROSPER",
          "correct": "succeed"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REAP the corn.",
          "answers": [
            "harvest",
            "boil",
            "store",
            "plant",
            "buy"
          ],
          "word": "REAP",
          "correct": "harvest"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Large CAVITY.",
          "answers": [
            "pile",
            "stain",
            "tooth",
            "hole",
            "cut"
          ],
          "word": "_",
          "correct": "hole"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Will it SHRIVEL?",
          "answers": [
            "leak",
            "squeak",
            "shrink",
            "stop",
            "grow"
          ],
          "word": "SHRIVEL",
          "correct": "shrink"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To SLAY them.",
          "answers": [
            "kill",
            "hide",
            "spread",
            "strike",
            "cure"
          ],
          "word": "SLAY",
          "correct": "kill"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will THRASH us.",
          "answers": [
            "bite",
            "kill",
            "tie",
            "beat",
            "thank"
          ],
          "word": "THRASH",
          "correct": "beat"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "General ACQUAINTANCE.",
          "answers": [
            "love",
            "excellence",
            "ignorance",
            "familiarity",
            "oddity"
          ],
          "word": "ACQUAINTANCE",
          "correct": "familiarity"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "At the BANQUET.",
          "answers": [
            "dance",
            "feast",
            "bar",
            "meeting",
            "game"
          ],
          "word": "BANQUET",
          "correct": "feast"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REDUCE tension.",
          "answers": [
            "fight",
            "increase",
            "cause",
            "lessen",
            "end"
          ],
          "word": "REDUCE",
          "correct": "lessen"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was BLOATED.",
          "answers": [
            "under water",
            "scratched",
            "swollen",
            "diseased",
            "shrunken"
          ],
          "word": "BLOATED",
          "correct": "swollen"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CLUTCH them.",
          "answers": [
            "ruin",
            "steal",
            "hide",
            "release",
            "seize"
          ],
          "word": "CLUTCH",
          "correct": "seize"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Caused him to STAGGER.",
          "answers": [
            "jump back",
            "fall down",
            "choke",
            "scream",
            "move unsteadily"
          ],
          "word": "STAGGER",
          "correct": "move unsteadily"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His COMMITMENT.",
          "answers": [
            "feeling",
            "refusal",
            "crime",
            "pledge",
            "desire"
          ],
          "word": "COMMITMENT",
          "correct": "pledge"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the DEBRIS.",
          "answers": [
            "paper",
            "party",
            "ruins",
            "building",
            "riot"
          ],
          "word": "DEBRIS",
          "correct": "ruins"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "If two stories CONFLICT, are they the same?",
          "word": "CONFLICT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people want to PROSPER?",
          "word": "PROSPER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a farmer REAP corn before he plants it?",
          "word": "REAP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are CAVITIES always large?",
          "word": "CAVITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a balloon SHRIVEL when it is blown up?",
          "word": "SHRIVEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Have you ever been SLAIN?",
          "word": "SLAY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people dislike being THRASHED?",
          "word": "THRASH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should an auto mechanic have some ACQUAINTANCE with engines?",
          "word": "ACQUAINTANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are most meals BANQUETS?",
          "word": "BANQUET",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there a REDUCTION in a child's size as he grows up?",
          "word": "REDUCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "1I. Is a BLOATED face pleasant to look at?",
          "word": "BLOATED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to CLUTCH something that is slippery?",
          "word": "CLUTCH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a punch make a person STAGGER?",
          "word": "STAGGER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When two people get married, do they make a COMMITMENT to each other?",
          "word": "COMMITMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a bomb produce a lot of DEBRIS?",
          "word": "DEBRIS",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Quite a CONFLICT broke out between the supporters and the opponents of the king.",
          "word": "CONFLICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She PROSPERED that her students would do well on the test.",
          "word": "PROSPER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The employee received fifty dollars for his suggestion, but the company REAPED the profits.",
          "word": "REAP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The doctor removed a large CAVITY that was growing on his skin.",
          "word": "CAVITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill started to SHRIVEL when he heard the funny story.",
          "word": "SHRIVEL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "David SLEW the giant Goliath with a stone.",
          "word": "SLAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mr. White threatened to THRASH them if they ever stole anything from his store again.",
          "word": "THRASH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "You'll have to tell me what they're saying, since I am not ACQUAINTED with their language.",
          "word": "ACQUAINTANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The prince invited everyone to a huge BANQUET when he became king.",
          "word": "BANQUET",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The politician promised to REDUCE taxes, but instead they were increased.",
          "word": "REDUCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His stomach felt BLOATED after he ate the huge meal.",
          "word": "BLOATED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The drowning man CLUTCHED at the rope they threw to him.",
          "word": "CLUTCH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill was STAGGERED when the boss told him he was fired.",
          "word": "STAGGER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unless we have a firm COMMITMENT that the work will be completed by December 1st, we will not sign the agreement.",
          "word": "COMMITMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We had quite a DEBRIS when we won the championship.",
          "word": "DEBRIS",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CONFLICT",
          "answers": [
            "war",
            "fear",
            "quarrel"
          ],
          "word": "CONFLICT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROSPER",
          "answers": [
            "succeed",
            "protect",
            "thrive"
          ],
          "word": "PROSPER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REAP",
          "answers": [
            "gather",
            "profit",
            "seed"
          ],
          "word": "REAP",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CAVITY",
          "answers": [
            "stain",
            "gap",
            "hole"
          ],
          "word": "CAVITY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHRIVEL",
          "answers": [
            "wither",
            "confuse",
            "dry"
          ],
          "word": "SHRIVEL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SLAY",
          "answers": [
            "shoot",
            "stab",
            "rob"
          ],
          "word": "SLAY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "THRASH",
          "answers": [
            "throw",
            "whip",
            "pound"
          ],
          "word": "THRASH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACQUAINTANCE",
          "answers": [
            "knowledge",
            "friendship",
            "happiness"
          ],
          "word": "ACQUAINTANCE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BANQUET",
          "answers": [
            "food",
            "drink",
            "sleep"
          ],
          "word": "BANQUET",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REDUCE",
          "answers": [
            "decrease",
            "lessen",
            "widen"
          ],
          "word": "REDUCE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BLOATED",
          "answers": [
            "bloody",
            "enlarged",
            "stuffed"
          ],
          "word": "BLOATED",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CLUTCH",
          "answers": [
            "hold",
            "move",
            "grab"
          ],
          "word": "CLUTCH",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STAGGER",
          "answers": [
            "shock",
            "stop",
            "sway"
          ],
          "word": "STAGGER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMMITMENT",
          "answers": [
            "agreement",
            "hope",
            "promise"
          ],
          "word": "COMMITMENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEBRIS",
          "answers": [
            "litter",
            "rubble",
            "snow"
          ]
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}